Contact

linda.koppy@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lindakoppy-8347342 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing
Customer Service
Patient Safety

Certifications

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse

Basic Life Support

Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS)

Linda Koppy

Nursing Manager at MD Anderson Cancer Center Houston, Texas

Summary

Clinical Nurse in the Emergency Center/Clinical Decision Unit.

Transitioned after five years on Surgical Oncology unit, also serve as a Resource Nurse, Clinical Coach for new hires, Charge Nurse, and Chair of unit Education Committee. Graduated from The University of Texas Health Science Center (UTHealth) with a BSN in December 2012. Prior to attending nursing school, I earned my BBA from The University of Houston with a major in Operations Management, which focused on quality control and process improvement. My professional experience has helped me polish my communication skills, customer service, leadership and team building skills. My work ethic and strong desire to learn drives me to succeed and accomplish my goals.

Experience

MD Anderson Cancer Center
7 years 4 months

Nursing Manager

November 2019 - Present (8 months)

Clinical Nurse

March 2013 - November 2019 (6 years 9 months)

Texas Medical Center

Manage patient care and patient outcomes in collaboration with the multidisciplinary team. These duties include providing competent and compassionate care; administering medications, chemotherapy, and blood products; coordinating services for patient care; and continuity of care through appropriate discharge planning and patient education. The basic patient populations on the unit are patients with gynecological malignancies and patients undergoing inpatient radiation therapy. It also serves as the overflow unit for leukemia, lymphoma/myeloma, breast, GI and urology.

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Nursing Student

Page 1 of 3

May 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 8 months)

UTHealth School of Nursing Clinical Rotations:

- Methodist Sugar Land Hospital, General ICU and Emergency Department, Fall 2012
- Hospice Compassus, Omega House, and Thomas Street Health Center,
 Hospice and Palliative Care, and Community and Public Health, Fall 2012
- Memorial Hermann Northwest Hospital, Labor and Delivery, Nursery, and Postpartum, Summer 2012
- Texas Children's Hospital, General Pediatric Floors and Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, Summer 2012
- The Methodist Hospital, Transplant, Orthopedic, and Urology, Spring 2012
- Cypress Creek Hospital, Chemical Dependency, Adult and Adolescent Psychiatric Care, Spring 2012
- St. Luke's Episcopal Hospital, Adult Medical Surgical Unit, Summer 2011

Briggs & Veselka Co. Senior Associate, Business Advisory Services January 2008 - May 2011 (3 years 5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Managed relationships for client portfolio of various industries; Performed outsourced and co-sourced internal audit and consulting services; Made recommendations to management and presented audit reports to clients' Audit Committees; Supervised, mentored and developed internal audit staff; Created and implemented standardized audit programs for the department and transitioned to electronic work papers; Evaluated internal controls to assess the effectiveness of controls, efficiency of operations, and compliance with regulations.

Sterling Bank
Senior Internal Auditor
May 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 8 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Developed and executed integrated audit programs; Documented audit fieldwork in work papers and reported results to management; Prepared observations and recommendations based on work performed; Conducted exit meetings and prepared draft audit reports.

Crowell & Crowell, PLLC NOW Elliott Davis Decosimo Senior Associate October 2005 - April 2006 (7 months)

Greater Nashville Area, TN

Served in an outsourced capacity to evaluate internal controls and efficiency of operations; Documented controls and completed testing for regulatory compliance.

Crowe Horwath LLP
Senior Associate, Financial Institutions Group
April 2005 - October 2005 (7 months)
Greater Nashville Area, TN

Worked in a consulting capacity to evaluate internal controls and efficiency of operations; Documented controls, performed assessments and process walk throughs, and completed testing for regulatory compliance.

Sterling Bank (now Comerica Bank)
Senior Internal Auditor
October 2003 - March 2005 (1 year 6 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Documented internal controls and completed testing for regulatory compliance; Prepared observations and recommendations based on work performed; Conducted exit meetings and prepared draft audit reports; Provided assistance to external audit personnel as necessary; Completed special projects and special investigations as necessary.

Encore Bank (purchased by Cadence Bank)
Staff Auditor
April 1999 - October 2003 (4 years 7 months)

Evaluated internal controls to assess the effectiveness of controls and efficiency of operations.

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Bachelors of Science in Nursing, Nursing (2011 - 2012)

University of Houston
Bachelors of Business Administration, Operations Management